gamut.media 2016-11-22

# Gamut | Privacy Policy

Gamut is committed to privacy and to giving you choice in the advertising that you view. This privacy policy explains the types of data we intend to collect, how we use that data, and how long we keep it. We also provide you with the ability to opt out from receiving targeted advertising from advertisers and publishers (i.e., website owners) using our services.

What we DON’T Collect: Gamut does not intentionally collect any personally identifiable information and we don’t use any personally identifiable information to target advertising to you. We define “personally identifiable information” as information that would allow someone to know both your name and additional contact or financial information such as a telephone number, email address, complete street address, or credit card number.

About Children: Children are people too. We do NOT knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of 13, we will delete such information from our records. If we change our practices in the future, we will obtain prior, verifiable parental consent before collecting any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13.

Because we do not collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13, we also do NOT knowingly distribute such information to third parties.

What do we Collect? To deliver the most relevant advertising to you, Gamut collects anonymous data when you visit a site that uses our services. That data may include the URL of the site or page you visited, your IP address (which provides some level of geographic detail more general than zip codes), the time of day, and the category of ads that were presented to you or that you interacted with. We may collect information regarding the interaction (for example, pausing or rewinding a video advertisement). We may collect information that tells us what led you to the site within Gamut (referring URL or search query). This information is stored on our servers with a random numeric id – and we store that numeric ID, encrypted, in your browser as a cookie. Collectively, we refer to all of this information as “cookie targeting data”. None of this information can be used to personally identify you.

What we do with the data we collect: Using the cookie targeting data, we can specify characteristics shared by groups of users that may be desired for an advertising campaign (we only target ads against aggregated information). We can also use cookie targeting data to affect the number of times you are presented with a particular ad or set of ads within a period of time (so-called “frequency-capping”). For example, a pet food producer would like to present its product to consumers who live in the San Francisco Bay Area and are possibly interested, based on browsing history, in pets. If we determine that the Gamut cookie on your browser may be associated with viewing pet-related website and with an IP address in the San Francisco Bay Area, you may be more likely to be presented with an advertisement from that producer. And we determine otherwise, you may be less likely to be presented with an advertisement from that producer. Gamut does not have a mechanism for advertisers to know the personal identity of the person receiving the targeted advertisements. We may share with third parties aggregated, non-personally identifiable information, such as the number of users who visit a publisher site or the number of users who clicked on a particular advertisement. This information does not identify you individually. The examples of our use of cookie targeting information are not comprehensive. In general, we will use cookie targeted data to facilitate the requirements of advertisers so long as such use does not personally identify you.

Website Privacy Policies. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of the websites that you visit. You should contact website publishers directly should you have questions concerning their use of your information such as, for example, communications you may or may not wish to receive. We receive information about consumers from third parties to enable targeted advertising on the website(s) and application(s) that we support. The collection and use of that data is governed by the privacy policy and legal terms of the data collector and the website using the data; it is not governed by Gamut Smart Media.

How long do we keep the Data? Gamut stores cookie targeting data is for 60 days. Certain data, such as the category of ads on specific sites and pages are retained, in aggregate, to inform our decision engine for serving the most relevant ads to any consumer on a non-targeted basis. Frequency-capping cookie data is retained on the consumer’s browser for as long as specified in specific campaign requirements. Gamut’s servers do not store frequency-capping cookie data.

Opt Out Program. As part of our commitment to giving you control and transparency, we provide you with a way to determine if your browser has a Gamut cookie and a way to opt-out of receiving cookie-targeted online ads from networks hosted on Gamut’s platform. Click here to learn more.

FURTHER INFORMATION

If you have any questions about anything in this Privacy Policy, or about collection of personally identifiable information, or information generally, please contact Gamut via [help@gamut.media](mailto:help@gamut.media) or:

Gamut. Smart media from Cox., LLC  
Office of the General Counsel  
611 Gateway Blvd  
South San Francisco, CA  94080  
USA

###### Your browser’s current status
